import type { MCQ } from '../../../types'

export const mcqSet1: MCQ[] = [
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the first step in the data science methodology?",
    "options": [
      "Data Collection",
      "Business Understanding",
      "Modeling",
      "Evaluation"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which phase involves building predictive or descriptive models?",
    "options": [
      "Data Collection",
      "Data Understanding",
      "Modeling",
      "Evaluation"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What is the main goal of predictive analytics?",
    "options": [
      "To analyze past events",
      "To forecast future outcomes",
      "To summarize historical data",
      "To visualize data trends"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What type of predictive analytics method would be most suitable for forecasting sales trends over the next quarter?",
    "options": [
      "Classification",
      "Regression",
      "Time-series Analysis",
      "Anomaly Detection"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What type of machine learning method is classification?",
    "options": [
      "Unsupervised learning",
      "Supervised learning",
      "Reinforcement learning",
      "Semi-supervised learning"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which type of classifier involves the creation and application of rules, such as decision trees?",
    "options": [
      "Inductive/deductive classifiers",
      "Transudative classifiers",
      "Heuristics-based classifiers",
      "Probabilistic classifiers"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a metric used to evaluate the performance of a classification model?",
    "options": [
      "Accuracy",
      "Precision",
      "Root Mean Squared Error (RMSE)",
      "Recall"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "You are working with a large dataset with high dimensionality. Which classification algorithm might be a good choice for this scenario?",
    "options": [
      "Decision Tree",
      "K-Nearest Neighbors",
      "Naive Bayes",
      "Support Vector Machine"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What problem is indicated by an algorithm performing well on training data but poorly on testing data?",
    "options": [
      "Multicollinearity",
      "Underfitting",
      "Overfitting",
      "Homoscedasticity"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "In regression analysis, what is another name for the response variable?",
    "options": [
      "Target variable",
      "Predictor variable",
      "Independent variable",
      "Outlier variable"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  }
]
